WANG CHEN

PROFILE

Hi! I'm Wang CHEN, 3 years as Data Scientist, 6 years as Automotive Innovation engineer and also a full stack web developer. I specialise in connected services and manufacturing process optimization. I have multi country working experience, and speak 3 languages. I hope my experience in both engineering and data science could bridge the gap and create new value spaces.

EXPERIENCE

Faurecia Automotive Seating DATA SCIENTIST

France Sep 2019 - Present

- FaurSound for shopfloor noise quality control (Saving = ~200k EUR/year/production line)
- Occupant monitoring for drowsiness detection, posture evaluation (cockpit of the future)
- Build web app for real time manufacturing production data analysis
- Deploy ML model in constrained manufacturing environment
- Production line data analysis, explore 10 years production line data to optimise process
- Welding process quality inspection, use 3D welding scan data to verify welding quality
- Actively follow state of art research/papers and continuously learning
- Promote data mindset and provide training for internal colleagues













Faurecia Automotive Seating INNOVATION ENGINEER

France & China Jul 2013 - Spe 2019

- R&D engineer, Leading Simulation and Test activities
- Enjoy learning and quick adapt to new technologies
- Working at international environment, cooperate with worldwide colleagues and customers
- Cross function work with program, engineering, quality, plant, finance departments



Mechanical







EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.), Software engineering

Jiangnan University

Jan 2014 - Dec 2018

Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering

Jiangnan University

Jul 2009 - Jun 2013



+33 7 68 90 97 11

solid.chen9@gmail.com

wangchen.dev Normandy,France

Programming: Python,

JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

Frameworks: Tensorflow,

PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Next.js

Developer Tools: Linux, Git,

Docker, Kubernetes,

Azure devops

LANGUAGES

Chinese Native

English Full Professional

Proficiency

French Professional

Proficiency

CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning specialization

[Coursera]

Introduction to Self-Driving Cars

[Coursera]

Big Data methods and solutions

for data analysis [Orsys]

INTERESTS

Meditation

Travelling